

Patricia McPhee

SR UX TECHNICAL WRITER CONTENT DESIGNER CONTENT DEVELOPER

(425) 230-2037 hi@patriciamcphee.com patriciamcphee.github.io/portfolio/

About Me

I've been in IT for 25 years, starting in support and moving to network system administration. However, for the past 20 years, I've been a Technical Writer taking the guesswork out of complex technical content. I've also written around lousy user interface design through this time, so I've learned how to uncover and solve user experience (UX) challenges.

Education

02/2022 - Present

CareerFoundry

Full Stack Web Development

10/2010 - 05/2012

Kaplan University

BS in Health Science

02/1999 - 04/2001

DeVry University - Denver

AS Computer Systems

Page 1

Work Experience

05/2020 - 10/2021

Content Developer, Contractor Microsoft/Kforce

Worked collaboratively with the Azure VMware Solution core engineering and UX Research teams to develop scenario and goal-based content. Write and edit UX microcopy and UI strings. Conduct audits of existing content to identify areas for improvement. Use qualitative and quantitative data to make data-driven decisions.

07/2019 - 06/2021

Freelance

- Extreme Networks (2020 2021) Reviewed and edited network hardware content for the FIPS program.
- **Netdata (2020)** Wrote product content for a Linux server performance tool.
- **ZPE Systems (2019-2020)** Wrote a marketing campaign eBook. Wrote video scripts, provided the voiceover, and produced how-to videos.
- Wax.io (2019) Contributed to blockchain blog articles.

03/2019 - 06/2019

Technical Writer II

LivePerson

Wrote SDK and API guides for mobile messaging app.

01/2018 - 01/2019

Technical Writer II

Microsoft

Worked collaboratively with the Microsoft Edge and Windows networking core teams. Wrote and edited UX microcopy and UI strings. Conducted content audits to identify areas for potential improvement. Used qualitative and quantitative data to make data-driven decisions.

07/2017 - 12/2017

Technical Writer, Contractor

Oculus/Facebook

Developed internal cross-functional workflows and process documentation for a virtual reality R&D environment.

08/2016 - 05/2017

Software Technical Writer

GE Healthcare

Worked collaboratively with customers and support to update the outdated installation and upgrade guides. The rework resulted in more successful upgrades and reduced customer support calls.



Skills

Technical Writing

Content Strategy

UX/UI Writing

Information Architecture

Project Management

Instructional Design

DITA/oXygen

Markdown

Git/GitHub

Agile/Jira/Azure DevOps

Bootstrap 5

JavaScript

HTML/CSS

Figma/Adobe XD

Work Experience (cont'd)

09/2015 - 07/2016

Technical Writer II

Amazon

Wrote internal feature announcements and task-oriented procedure guides for warehouse employees.

03/2015 - 09/2015

Technical Writer, Contractor

Charter Communications

Worked collaboratively with video-on-demand and networking engineers to write standard procedures. Wrote Python scripts for system administration tasks.

01/2014 - 10/2014

Technical Writer

SolidFire, a NetApp company

Wrote release notes, configuration and troubleshooting guides, white papers, and solution briefs for the cloud storage solution. Also, wrote and edited UX microcopy and UI strings.

12/2012 - 12/2013

Technical Writer, Contractor

Sybase/SAP

Wrote installation, configuration, and API guides for a mobile money app.

07/2012 - 01/2013

Technical Writer Consultant

Wrote design specifications and instructor-led training guides for enterprise planning and budgeting software. Also, wrote and edited UX microcopy and UI strings.

Achievements

- Built an online help system using the Docusaurus docs-as-code framework for a tech security startup.
- Wrote shell scripts to automate OpenAPI content publishing for Extreme Networks.
- Built a custom authoring environment in MadCap Flare and converted legacy content for several large corporations, maximizing content reuse and to reducing the cost of creating, managing, and publishing content.